

## CONTACT

Yalapa, Veracruz, México



estorresag2019@gmail.com



4426147355

in https://www.linkedin.com/in /esmeralda-torres-aguirre/

## LANGUAGES

Spanish (native speaker) English B2

## PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

HTML & CSS Javascript ReactJS NodeJS TypeScript Git, Github and GitLab Microsoft Office basics iOS system Firebase

## **SOFT SKILLS**

Learning attitude Comunication Creativity Perseverance Leadership Honesty

## **PROJECTS LINK**

- https://digital-invite-byesmeralda.vercel.app/
- https://www.bodas.com.mx/invitaciones-deboda/digital-invite-by-esmeralda--e391154
- https://personal-portfolioesmeralda.vercel.app/
- https://github.com/EsmeraldaTorres
- https://social-github-api.vercel.app/
- https://stoic-dubinsky-e9cac2.netlify.app/

# **ESMERALDA TORRES AGUIRRE**

#### FRONTEND DEVELOPER

As a frontend developer, with 3 years of experience, I learned how to troubleshoot API connections and improve code functionality in React combined with the HCL Commerce environment. As a freelancer I develop and digitize responsive invitations for events using HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, Firebase and other design frameworks.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### FREELANCE DEVELOPER

DIGITAL INVITE BY ESMERALDA / AGOSTO 2022 - CURRENT

- Design and develop web pages such as digital invitations for different events such as weddings and social events.
- Community manager of my own businesses.
- Develop with HTML, CSS, Javascript, React and Firebase.
- Attention and treatment with clients.

#### **REACT DEVELOPER**

GRUPO STI / AUGUST 2022 - NOVEMBER 2023

- Support and development of new E-commerce functionalities such as forms, add or remove products to cart, pop up information for the user.
- Basic functionalities with HCL commerce such as: Make landing pages. (Markenting Content and Spots)
- API Connections, React and Typescript, Axios.

#### **TEACHING**

PRIVATE TEACHER OF BASIC MUSIC / 2019 SUBSTITUTE

TEACHER OF BASIC ENGLISH AT UNIVERSIDAD VASCONSELOS DE TABASCO / 2017

## **EDUCATION HISTORY**

#### FRONT END DEVELOPER

ACADEMLO BOOTCAMP AS STUDENT 2020 / 2024

- HTML, Css and Javascript consuming API.
- React: Projects like make a To Do List, e-commerce and consuming APIS to pages like Weather, Github users and World Flag's.
- Make APIs whit MVC model on NodeJS

#### **DEGREE DIGITAL DESIGN**

UNIVERSIDAD TECNOLÓGICA DE MÉXICO / 2018-2021

• Graduated by high grade point average and knowledge of the English language.